<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>I must follow, if I can</title>
    
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving to Medium</title>
        <description>
          
          After all the shenanigans over at WordPress, I&apos;ve decided to start publishing on Medium. You can follow me there if you like. I have 15 subscribers here, so I&apos;ll probably be importing you over there after the waiting period is over. I don&apos;t know yet all the ins-and-outs of how...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 13:29:10 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/10/11/moving-to-medium/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/10/11/moving-to-medium/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>According to E&amp;amp;E News, Trump used Politics when Deciding Whether to Render Aid in the Camp Fire</title>
        <description>
          
          (Image source: Yichuan Cao / Sipa USA via AP) Remember when Trump visited the town of &quot;Pleasure&quot; (our town&apos;s name is Paradise, which also starts with the letter P and means something intrinsically nice) after the Camp Fire in 2018? Well, apparently he did a background check on us first....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 09:29:50 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/10/06/trump-used-politics-when-deciding-whether-to-render-aid-in-the-camp-fire/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/10/06/trump-used-politics-when-deciding-whether-to-render-aid-in-the-camp-fire/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Eschatological Roots of Our Predicament</title>
        <description>
          
          Background I&apos;m currently going through a bunch of old notes. Since Evernote raised prices and locked down free accounts a long time ago, I&apos;ve tried importing them to Notion, and today I imported to Apple Notes. But most of my note-taking is for work, and I need screenshots on Windows...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 17:27:30 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/10/05/the-eschatological-roots-of-our-predicament/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/10/05/the-eschatological-roots-of-our-predicament/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Review—The Exvangelicals: Loving, Living, and Leaving the White Evangelical Church</title>
        <description>
          
          Sarah McCammon is an NPR journalist who was assigned to cover the Trump campaign in 2016. The Exvangelicals is part memoir and part reporting about that state of the church and why so many are leaving. I identified with the book all the way through, as I grew up in...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 10:39:56 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/09/01/the-exvangelicals-loving-living-and-leaving-the-white-evangelical-church/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/09/01/the-exvangelicals-loving-living-and-leaving-the-white-evangelical-church/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Concerning Fires</title>
        <description>
          
          On July 24, 2024, at Upper Park in Chico, California, a man set his car on fire and pushed it off a 60-foot embankment. The dry vegetation around it was quickly engulfed in flames and the fire spread rapidly, climbing the ridge into the forest and eventually growing over 400,000...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 19:28:47 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/03/concerning-fires/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/08/03/concerning-fires/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deconstruction Reading List</title>
        <description>
          
          I would like this book list to correspond to a sort of roadmap, a progression from, say, a mainline Christian to a full-blown ethical progressive atheist and humanist, who has a sure foundation for morality apart from religion. I&apos;m not all the way there yet, as I have some books...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 09:04:20 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/30/a-deconstruction-reading-list/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/30/a-deconstruction-reading-list/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Owning your Accomplishments</title>
        <description>
          
          I don’t talk about it much, especially as time has passed and I’ve moved on with my life, but 25 years ago I was in a band. We recorded a demo, and then the lead singer signed a record contract. We changed our name and re-recorded the demo material along...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:58:55 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/27/owning-your-accomplishments/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/27/owning-your-accomplishments/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Annihilationism and Your Pet Cat</title>
        <description>
          
          I was a Calvinist before I became an atheist. I was very Calvinist, in fact. It got to the point where I had eventually achieved such a robust Reformation theology that I accepted the idea that God could actually choose to send me to hell for eternity. I figured if...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 21:58:56 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/26/annihilationism-and-your-pet-cat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/26/annihilationism-and-your-pet-cat/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When I was an Agnostic</title>
        <description>
          
          These words were penned 10 years ago. I never got around to blogging them because blogging was out of fashion at the time, in favor of micro-blogging platforms such as Twitter (R.I.P.) and due to other distractions in life. But it illustrates a step on my thought journey. Dated March...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 09:57:28 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/23/when-i-was-an-agnostic/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/23/when-i-was-an-agnostic/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Theodicy, Slavery, and CSA</title>
        <description>
          
          Since I began deconstructing my faith 10-12 years ago, I have been keeping notes in Evernote with various tags (later Notion, as I had to abandon Evernote due to its constantly-increasing fees and restrictions). I even made a Mind Map of all the points I had developed. Two of the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 15:31:04 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/20/theodicy-slavery-and-csa/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/20/theodicy-slavery-and-csa/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on Dystheism and the Sacrifice of Isaac</title>
        <description>
          
          They say: When God does good, it&apos;s not because he&apos;s conforming himself to some external morality; God&apos;s actions are good because it is God doing them. Goodness is whatever God does and commands. This is the absolutist&apos;s reply to Euthyphro&apos;s dilemma. But maybe the absolutist is wrong. By way of...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 10:45:11 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/16/thoughts-on-dystheism-and-the-sacrifice-of-isaac/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/16/thoughts-on-dystheism-and-the-sacrifice-of-isaac/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory &amp;#8211; Book Review</title>
        <description>
          
          Tim Alberta&apos;s The Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory is a great book. The author&apos;s intended purpose is to investigate the errors that have allowed MAGA extremism to permeate the evangelical church. The book&apos;s overall sentiment can be summarized by this quote from a passage where the author was interviewing...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 15:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/12/the-kingdom-the-power-and-the-glory-book-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/12/the-kingdom-the-power-and-the-glory-book-review/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dystheism vs. Theodicy</title>
        <description>
          
          The problem of evil, or, &quot;Why does God allow bad things to happen?&quot; There are two categories that are really pivotal in my thoughts and opinions on theism in the last decade. These are &quot;theodicy&quot; and &quot;dystheism&quot;.&amp;nbsp;The definitions of these terms are very similar, and I wouldn&apos;t be surprised if...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:15:38 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/dystheism-vs-theodicy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/dystheism-vs-theodicy/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New blog home</title>
        <description>
          
          I&apos;ve migrated my blog from mustfollow.wordpress.com to mustfollow.blog, and then off of Automattic&apos;s Wordpress.com entirely to self-hosted, now at blog.lorddev.com. I&apos;ve changed the theme as my previous one was quite outdated. But the Tolkien quote doesn&apos;t really fit anymore, so I need to think of a new blog title. I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:15:05 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/04/new-blog-home/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/03/04/new-blog-home/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Defending Democracy from Christian Nationalists</title>
        <description>
          
          The Baptists had insisted that the way Jesus made disciples was by teaching and persuasion, not by coercion. They held that the government has no competence in religion, and when it seeks to enforce faith it creates wars of religion and hypocrites who claim a faith they do not actually...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 09:42:14 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/31/defending-democracy-from-christian-nationalists/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/12/31/defending-democracy-from-christian-nationalists/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Music for fun vs. music for religion</title>
        <description>
          
          In my youth I exhibited an acumen for music and was told by my parents that I was to do it all &quot;to the glory of God&quot; (1 Cor. 10:31). Though I studied classical music I was sort of sending energy to the Most High while I played it. My...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:38:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/03/music-for-fun/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/03/music-for-fun/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Odyssey of Theodicy</title>
        <description>
          
          Theodicy is the attempt to vindicate God when we see so much evil in the world. During the first phase of my deconstruction, my own theodocious issues weren&apos;t quite the same as others. For me, the problem of evil was addressed with by Calvinism and the doctrine of Original Sin....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:49:22 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/10/29/the-odyssey-of-theodicy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/10/29/the-odyssey-of-theodicy/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Faith and depression</title>
        <description>
          
          “The joy of the Lord.” I’ve never felt it. In 2016 my grandma died. The year before that, my other grandma died. In 2018 our house burned to the ground in the Camp fire (along with the whole rest of the town). I am well-acquainted with grief. And when I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 11:38:47 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/28/faith-and-depression/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/12/28/faith-and-depression/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Put another way&amp;#8230;</title>
        <description>
          
          My dad is a worship leader. He proposed to my mom with the “God told me you’re supposed to be my wife” pitch. He gave me names from the bible—“Aaron” and “Jacob”—and he said God showed him some bible verses that applied to me prophetically, to the effect that I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 09:35:55 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/21/put-another-way/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/12/21/put-another-way/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Reformed Theology taught me to be a Freethinker</title>
        <description>
          
          All truth is God&apos;s truth. —Augustine A wise man proportions his belief to the evidence. —David Hume Bertrand Russell said, “Perhaps you may say that it would be rather a pity if Christian education were to cease, because you would then get no more Rationalists.” I concur (though I admit...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 12:04:55 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/14/how-reformed-theology-taught-me-to-be-a-freethinker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/12/14/how-reformed-theology-taught-me-to-be-a-freethinker/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>